MD RASHID HUSSAIN

Full Stack Developer

I am a passionate and innovative full-stack developer for more than two years now. Working with tight deadlines and strict requirements has sharpened my logical, analytical, and collaboration skills over time. Most of the tools, I use are open-source software, and contributed to various open-source projects.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

- Optimized frontend build times from 72 minutes to 11 minutes
- Set up CI/CD for automatic deployments to AWS
- Implemented the "custom dashboard builder" feature from scratch
- Used: React, React Native, Linux, BASH, GitHub Actions, AWS S3, AWS Amplify

Meta16Labs - SDE Intern Feb 2022 - May 2022

- Worked with OPD, Camps, Patient journey and history management on MetaHOS software
- Implemented the WhatsApp and SMS services on the backend
- Used: React, React Native, NodeJs, ExpressJs, AWS S3, MongoDB

Vinnovate Technologies - SDE Intern

i Dec 2021 - Jan 2022

- Implemented bulk uploads feature over web sockets and OCR of bills and resume
- Automated the process of PDF making, parsing, internal linking, and dynamic changes according to inputs and directions taken from Excel and CSV files
- Used: React, NodeJs, ExpressJs, MongoDB

PROJECTS

- Objective and Subjective exam papers, accounts management of all involved parties, etc
- Analytics and dashboards for student Performance, overall test paper, dashboards, etc.
- Currently used in production with an academic organization in singapore
- Used: React, NodeJs, ExpressJs, MongoDB, AWS EC2, Cloudflare

Hospital Management System

- **Aug 2022 Feb 2023**
- Real-Time Hospital management application intended for JMI Health Centre
- Available as a web and native desktop app for Windows & Debian-based Linux distros
- Currently in production and used on the JMI Internal Network
- Used: React, NodeJs, ExpressJs, PostgreSQL, Rust, Tauri

- A social media application with toxicity analysis of all user posts and real-time chat and full admin controls to remove, create and modify users, topics, posts, etc.
- Used: React, NodeJs, ExpressJs, PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQL Server, Azure, Cloudflare

ZUNI = Dec 2021 - Dec 2021

- Web application where Users register with a username and their face as a password
- The system is smart enough to distinguish a real face from a printed face, a face on the screen, an image with multiple faces, etc.
- Used: React, Netlify, SCSS, Flask, SQLite, PyTorch, Tensorflow

TAX TDS Sept 2021 - Feb 2022

- A local business and finance directory website where users register their services and public can quote for those services
- Equipped with all services like auth, mailer, uploads, notifications, etc.
- Used: React, Typescript, TailwindCSS, NodeJs, ExpressJs, EJS, MongoDB

VOLUNTEER WORK

Shiksha Sopan, IIT Kanpur

Frontend Developer

- May 2022 July 2022
- Collaborated on NAEST exam portal
- Worked with Dr. HC Verma Sir and other amazing people at Sopan ashram
- Used : React, Typescript

WORKED WITH

- Languages: Javascript, Typescript, Go, Python, C/C++, Rust, SQL
- Frameworks: Express, NodeJs, Go-Fiber, Flask
- Databases: MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL
- CDNs: CloudFlare, Surge, AWS Amplify, Netlify
- AWS: EC2, S3, RDS, Amplify, Cloudfront
- CI/CD: Github Actions
- Shell Scripting: BASH
- Tools: Ubuntu Linux, Git + GitHub, VSCode/WebStorm, Android Studio

SKILLS

- Critical Thinking, Problem Solving
- Self Critic Accountability
- Collaboration/Teamwork
- Communication, Presentation Skills

EDUCATION

B.Tech. in Computer Science
Jamia Millia Islamia 9.69 CPI

2020 - 2024

Intermediate Science (PCM) SHSSS. AMU 83.2

2017 - 2019

Elementory & High School

D.A.V. Public School 10 CGPA

2005 - 2017